Marc Franco Salvador

Valencia, 46184, Valencian Community, Spain

E-mail: <u>marc.franco@symanto.com</u> – LinkedIn: <u>es.linkedin.com/in/marfrasa/en</u> CV (extended version) in PDF

Summary

I am Chief Scientific Officer at Symanto, a data analytics company based on psycholinguistic profiling. In this role, I work with my team to provide our data analysis platform with novel solutions based on the latest techniques of natural language processing, machine and deep learning.

I have more than ten years of experience as a researcher in projects related to multilingual natural language processing and information retrieval. I have participated in more than ten R&D projects with national and international funding, in some of which I have been head and responsible of research. Those projects allowed me to acquire a strong background in machine and deep learning, data science, analytics, and mining.

I am a passionate, focused, and creative researcher. I like to read blogs and scientific papers about computational linguistics, data mining, and deep learning. In addition, I contribute to the scientific community by publishing articles in prestigious conferences and journals, and organizing shared tasks in national and international conferences.

I obtained my PhD in computer science in the Universitat Politècnica de València (Spain) with cum laude distinction, where I also obtained my Engineer's Degree in Computer Science and my Master's Degree in Artificial Intelligence, Pattern Recognition and Digital Image. During my career I have published more than 30 scientific articles, some of them in top conferences, and participated in several international research internships around the world.

Professional experience

Chief Scientific Officer

April 2022 - present

Symanto

- Head of the scientific department
- Person responsible for all scientific activities of Symanto (artificial intelligence, natural language processing, and deep learning)
- Responsible for aligning the scientific activities and objectives with the rest of the departments
- Represent the company in scientific matters

Scientific Advisor

August 2023 - present

Genaios

Deep Learning Lecturer - Big Data & Data Science Master
Institut de Formació Contínua IL3 - Universitat de Barcelona (UB)

May 2022 - present

• Responsible of the deep learning teaching. Creation of training content and activities, correction of exercises, teaching of theory and practice, conducting tutorship sessions

Scientific Advisor

April 2022 – present

AI Zwei

Scientific Advisor

September 2021 - present

Coinradar.ai

City lead - Valencia AI

Spain AI

Responsible for Valencia (Valencia AI) for the Spain AI platform. Organization of seminars on topics related to artificial intelligence

Director of Research

Feb 2021 - Mar 2022

Symanto

- Person in charge of the research department and its AI & NLP solutions
- Decision making and supervision of all the aspects related to the research activities of the
- Responsible for aligning research activities and objectives with the rest of the company's departments

Collaborator - Big Data & Data Science Master

June 2021 - July 2021

Institut de Formació Contínua IL3 - Universitat de Barcelona (UB)

Responsible for the topic on deep learning applied to natural language processing. Creation of training content and activities, correction of exercises, teaching of theory and practice, conducting tutorship sessions

Principal Research Scientist

May 2018 - Jan 2021

Symanto

- Person in charge of the research staff
- Decision making on new lines of research and their implementation
- Supervision and participation in the development of the new artificial intelligence-based solutions

Innovation Lead

Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

Symanto

- Lead a team of data scientists and psycholinguists
- Provide the data analysis platform with novel solutions based on the latest techniques of natural language processing and deep learning

Data Scientist

Dec 2016 - Apr 2017

Symanto

- Research on cross-lingual and cross-domain deep learning solutions
- Application of data science techniques to text analytics

Research Fellow

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Data and Web Science Group, Universität Mannheim

Research on several natural language processing projects

Data Scientist

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Symanto

- Research on cross-lingual deep learning solutions
- Application of data science techniques to text analytics

Senior Technician - NLP researcher

Jul 2014 - May 2016

PRHLT Research Center, Universitat Politècnica de València

- SOMEMBED research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness
- DIANA-APPLICATIONS research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness

April 2021 – present

Technical Specialist - NLP researcher

Apr 2014 - Jun 2014

Italica Research Group, University of Seville

• DOCGU research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness

Research Fellow

Apr 2013 - Mar 2014

Linguistic Computing Laboratory, Sapienza University of Rome

MultiJEDI research project, funded by the 5-year ERC Starting Grant No. 259234

Senior Technician - NLP researcher

Aug 2012 - Dec 2012

NLE Lab, Universitat Politècnica de València

• TEXT-ENTERPRISE 2.0 research project, funded by the Spanish Ministry of Education and Science

Education

PhD in Natural Language Processing and Information Retrieval

Mar 2013 - May 2017

Universitat Politècnica de València, Valencia, Spain

- Title: A Cross-domain and Cross-language Knowledge-based Representation of Text and its Meaning
- Score: Cum laude (international distinction)

MSc in Artificial Intelligence, Pattern Recognition and Digital Image

Sep 2011 - Feb 2013

Universitat Politècnica de València, Valencia, Spain

- Title: Cross-Language Plagiarism Detection using a Multilingual Semantic Network
- Final score: Cum laude

BSc in Computer Science Engineering (5-year degree)

Sep 2006 - Sep 2011

<u>Universitat Politècnica de València</u>, Valencia, Spain

• Specialization in Artificial Intelligence and Languages

Publications

Available on Google Scholar: goo.gl/srdC6D

Certifications and courses

Available on LinkedIn: https://es.linkedin.com/in/marfrasa/en

References

Available upon request.